retail-surveycentral.net 2011-12-25

# Coolsavings

Last Updated: October 17, 2011

CoolSavings’ practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information while on www.coolsavings.com.  TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us [_**here**_](http://reg.coolsavings.com/info.htm?tp=con&promo_name=&catalog_id=14078).  If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). ****

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this policy explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this policy easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested.

This policy applies to all information collected or submitted on the CoolSavings website. CoolSavings is a website that provides you with the opportunity to get all your savings in one place, including access to printable coupons, coupon codes, free samples, product deals, national and local deals and much more. We collect information you provide on our website, including but not limited to your name, street address, e-mail address, telephone number (home, work and/or mobile), date of birth, and other personal, financial, or demographic information. 

Other ways in which we may collection information:

  * **Surveys or Contests**

From time-to-time, we may provide you the opportunity to participate in surveys or contests through CoolSavings or through one of our trusted partners who may operate the survey or contest. If you participate, we or our trusted partners may request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). We may use this information as described in this policy and to improve our sites, monitor site traffic or personalize the sites. 

  * **Testimonials**

From time-to-time, we may provide you the opportunity to provide testimonials about Cool Savings. We receive permission to post testimonials that include personally identifiable information prior to posting to CoolSavings. 

  * **Tell-A-Friend**

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our website, we will ask you for your friend’s name and contact information.  We will automatically send your friend a one-time communication inviting him or her to visit CoolSavings.  Cool Savings stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time communication and tracking the success of our referral program.

_Newsletters and Special Offers_

We will occasionally communicate with you  about products, services, special deals, and promotions.  You can sign up for these communications by becoming a registered member of CoolSavings. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications.  Please see the “Choice/Opt-out” section below. 

_Service-Related Announcements and Updates_

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so.  For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance or if new features or services are added to Cool Savings, we may send you a communication. 

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature.  If you do not wish to receive them, please [_**contact us**_](http://reg.coolsavings.com/info.htm?tp=con&promo_name=&catalog_id=14078).

_Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)_

We share aggregated demographic, performance and behavioral information about our user base with our partners and advertisers.  This information does not identify individual users.

 _Personally identifiable information:_

  * We may share your personal information with other companies so that they can empower their services, market their products or services to you and supply you with special offers.  We will only share information that we feel is the minimum required to fulfill those company’s requirements.  If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, please refer to the Choice/Opt-out section or change your preferences in “My Preferences”. 
  * We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as a hosting provider or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information _only as necessary to provide_ these services to us 
  * We may provide your personal information to specific companies who have their products and services advertised on the CoolSavings website.  For example, we may provide your personal information to an advertiser if you have taken an action to register for or request more information from an advertiser on CoolSavings.
  * We may also disclose your personal information 
    * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process 
    * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request,
    * if CoolSavings is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets,  you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information, 
    * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so. For example, when registering on the Community section of the CoolSavings website, your personal information is shared with NING, who operates the platform for the Community section on behalf of CoolSavings.

We provide you the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, such as marketing material from us or third party partners.

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by changing your preferences in “My Preferences”.

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. When you enter sensitive information (such as regulated and controlled data), we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

If your personally identifiable information changes, you may submit those changes through the My Preferences section of the website.  If you request deletion of your information previously collected, please note that your personal information will be suppressed from further use as described in this policy.  However, we will retain and use your personal information as necessary in order to comply with our corporate policies, including but not limited to legal obligations, dispute resolution and enforcement of our agreements. To submit such as request concerning the personal information we previously collected contact us [_**here**_](http://reg.coolsavings.com/info.htm?tp=con&promo_name=&catalog_id=14078). We will respond to your request within 30 days.

Protecting the privacy of children is especially important. For this reason, we never knowingly collect information from anyone under the age of 13. If we obtain actual knowledge that such information has been collected, that information will be immediately suppressed from our database.

Our website use cookies to enhance and personalize your online experience and to enable our website to recognize you as a previous visitor. A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a website's computer and stored on your computer's hard drive. You can adjust the settings on your browser to erase or block such technologies from your computer if you want to, but if you do so, you may experience difficulty using or accessing CoolSavings.

Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other websites. Many websites do this whenever a user visits their website in order to track online traffic flows. Cookies record information about your online preferences and may be tied to your personally identifiable information such as your email address for these purposes. Users have the opportunity to set their computers to accept all cookies, to notify them when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

We and third parties employ a software technology called Web Beacons that help us better manage content on our website by informing us what content is effective.  Web Beacons are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users.  In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, Web Beacons are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We may tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information such as their email address, to enhance and personalize content and your online experience.

We use Web Beacons in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients.  This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.  If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see “Choice/Opt-out.” 

Our website also allows its partners and advertisers that are presenting advertisements on the CoolSavings website to set their cookies, or apply Web Beacons or similar technologies, to your computer. We have no access or control of these third party tracking technologies. This information may be used to: 

  1. provide security;
  2. authenticate your Login;
  3. personalize features on the CoolSavings website;
  4. enable you to participate in certain online activities, such as making sure that each person only votes in an online poll once;
  5. help measure and research the effectiveness of the CoolSavings website, including collecting statistics on your response to advertisements, e-mail and other communications you receive;
  6. remember the preferences and registration data that you give us.

Our website and our associated third parties may also use ad network providers to help present advertisements on the Cool Savings website. These ad network providers may use cookies, or Web Beacons or similar technologies on your computer to tailor content, advertisements to your preferences, help target, measure and track your visits and the effectiveness of advertisements and promotions, using data gathered over time and across their networks of Web pages to determine or predict the characteristics and preferences of their audience and to provide security within shopping baskets or transactions. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. If you do not wish to have this information used by certain ad network providers for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking here: <http://preferences.truste.com/>. Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads. You may find more information at the website of either the individual third-party ad network, the Network Advertising Initiative (http://www.networkadvertising.org), Privacy Choice (http://www.privacychoice.org/choose), and Digital Advertising Alliance (http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information to analyze trends, to administer the website, to track users’ movements around the website and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

We may link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information to document your registration IP address, date and time, detect and investigate malicious activity, as necessary, comply with our corporate policies, including but not limited to legal obligations, dispute resolution and enforcement of our agreements and to assist us with enhancing and personalizing content and your online experience. 

We use a third-party tracking service that uses cookies and clear gifs to track non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our website in the aggregate to track usage and volume statistics to improve our website.

This website contains links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by CoolSavings.  Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our website and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information.

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by the CoolSavings website.

Our offer pages and other pages on our website may be powered by third parties that are either acting as a service provider for us or in some other cases may own and control the data collected (for. Ex. our Community pages).  Please view the privacy statement that links from each page on our website to understand these relationships.

We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email or by means of prominent notice on our website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

Should you have other questions or concerns about this policy, please [_**contact us**_](http://reg.coolsavings.com/info.htm?tp=con&promo_name=&catalog_id=14078).

CoolSavings Privacy, One North Dearborn Street, 12th Floor Chicago, Illinois 60602

If you are a California resident or another state with specific laws relating to the collection and use of Information, you may have specific rights not set forth in this policy. For example, California residents have the right to receive: a) information identifying any third party company(ies) to whom we may have disclosed, within the past calendar year, personal information pertaining to you and your family for the company's direct marketing purposes; and b) a description of the categories of personal information disclosed. To obtain such information you must make a request in writing. Your request must include your registration email address, the site name you visited and a return address or it will not be processed. We will not honor such requests more than once per calendar year. Requests made via email will not be accepted. Please mail your request to Customer Service Manager at the address listed in the footer of this site or the [_**contact us**_](http://reg.coolsavings.com/info.htm?tp=con&promo_name=&catalog_id=14078) page.
